Register of the Josef Škvorecký Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, 1908-1994. (Box 73-79)
  - Prints
    - Correspondence
      - Jirous, Ivan M., n.d. (Folder 75: 15)
      - Justl, Vladimír, 1989. (Folder 75: 16)
      - Kalus, Milan, 1981. (Folder 75: 17)
        3 color prints depicting Dr. Cepek
      - Karlovský, Adolf F. J., 1980-1992. (Folder 75: 18)
        4 color prints depicting Adolf F. J. Karlovský, 2 color prints depicting his wife, 4 color prints depicting crests, 1 black and white print depicting a goblet
      - Kepka, Ondřej, n.d. (Folder 75: 19)
        8 unidentified color prints
      - Klanger, Zdeněk, n.d.. (Folder 75: 20)
        4 unidentified black and white prints
      - Klíma, Ivan, 1982. (Folder 75: 21)
        3 black and white prints depicting Ivan Klíma
      - Kliment, Alexandr, n.d. (Folder 75: 22)
        1 black and white print depicting Alexandr Kliment, 2 unidentified black and white prints
      - Klobouk, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 75: 23)
        1 color print depicting Jiří Klobouk
      - Kohout, Jára, 1987. (Folder 75: 24)
        1 color print depicting Jára Kohout
      - Kohout, Pavel, 1978-1988. (Folder 75: 25)
        5 black and white and 4 color prints depicting Jelena and Pavel Kohout and family members
      - Kohoutová, Kateřina, 1991. (Folder 75: 26)
      - Kolář, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 75: 27)
      - Kolman, Arnošt, n.d. (Folder 75: 28)
        1 black and white print depicting Arnošt Kolman
      - Konopásek, Jan, n.d. (Folder 75: 29)
        2 color prints depicting Jan Konopásek and family members, 1 black and white print depicting Jan Konopásek, Karel Krautgartner and Woody Herman
      - Kovályová, Heda, n.d. (Folder 75: 30)
        1 black and white print depicting Heda Kovályová
      - Král, Petr, n.d. (Folder 75: 31)
        1 unidentified black and white print, 1 unidentified color print
      - Kratochvil, Antonín, 1984. (Box-folder 76: 1)
        1 black and white print depicting Antonín Kratochvil
      - Kriseová, Eda, n.d. (Folder 76: 2)
        6 black and white prints depicting Eda Kriseová
      - Krištof, Vašek, 1989-1991. (Folder 76: 3)
        18 color prints depicting an exhibition of Sixty-Eight Publishers, 1 color print depicting Vašek Krištof and family members
      - Kryl, Karel, n.d. (Folder 76: 4)
        6 black and white prints depicting Karel Kryl
      - Kubešová, Blanka, n.d. (Folder 76: 5)
      - Kudelková, Anna, n.d. (Folder 76: 6)
        3 unidentified black and white prints
      - Kundera, Milan, ca. 1968-1975. (Folder 76: 7)
        1 black and white and 1 color print depicting Milan Kundera, 2 color prints depicting Josef Skvorecký and Milan Kundera at Niagara Falls, 1 color print depicting Zdena Kundera and Josef Skvorecký, 3 color prints depicting Zdena and Milan Kundera, 1 unidentified black and white print
      - Landovský, Pavel, n.d. (Folder 76: 8)
        2 color and 8 black and white prints depicting Pavel Landovský
      - Levy, Alan, 1973. (Folder 76: 9)
        1 black and white print depicting Alan and Valerie Levy
      - Linhartová, Věra, 1939. (Folder 76: 10)
        1 black and white print depicting Karel Teige, Toyen and Jindřich Heisler
      - Lustig, Arnošt, 1980. (Folder 76: 11)
      - Machulková, Inka, n.d. (Folder 76: 12)
      - Mareš, Stanislav, n.d. (Folder 76: 13)
        2 color prints depicting Stanislav Mareš
      - Matátko, Jindrich, 1981. (Folder 76: 14)
      - Medjuck, Joseph, n.d. (Folder 76: 15)
      - Menzel, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 76: 16)
        1 color print depicting Jiří Menzel
      - Miller, Arthur, 1987. (Folder 76: 17)
        4 black and white prints depicting Arthur Miller, 12 unidentified black and white prints
      - Moc, Stanislav, n.d. (Folder 76: 18)
        1 color print depicting Stanislav Moc
      - Morava, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 76: 19)
        2 black and white prints depicting Jiří Morava
      - Murray, Irena, 1984. (Folder 76: 20)
      - Nápravník, Milan, 1986-1987. (Folder 76: 21)
      - Navarová, Jarka, n.d. (Folder 76: 22)
      - Navrátilová, Martina, 1983. (Folder 76: 23)
        1 color print depicting Martina Navrátilová and Josef Skvorecký
      - Nejezchleba, Přemysl, 1978-1979. (Folder 76: 24)
        1 unidentified color print, 1 unidentified black and white print
      - Němec, Jan, 1985. (Folder 76: 25)
        1 color print depicting Veronica and Jan Němec
      - Nesvadba, Josef, n.d. (Folder 76: 26)
      - Novák, Jan, n.d. (Folder 76: 27)
        1 black and white print depicting Jan Novák, 1 unidentified black and white print
      - Novák, Josef and Vojtěch, 1985. (Folder 76: 28)
        42 unidentified black and white prints
      - Novotná, Zdena, n.d. (Box-folder 77: 1)
      - Novotných, 1980. (Folder 77: 2)
        10 unidentified black and white prints, 2 unidentified color prints
      - Ochová, Sheila, n.d. (Folder 77: 3)
        1 black and white print depicting Sheila Ochová
      - Opasek, Anastáz, 1975-1982. (Folder 77: 4)
        3 black and white and 2 color prints depicting Anastáz Opasek
      - Pachman, Luděk, n.d. (Folder 77: 5)
        1 black and white print depicting Luděk Pachman
      - Pfaff, Ivan, n.d. (Folder 77: 7)
        1 black and white print depicting Ivan Pfaff
      - Pilarová, Eva, n.d. (Folder 77: 8)
        3 color prints depicting Eva Pilarová
      - Planner, George, 1981, 1991. (Folder 77: 9)
      - Procházková, Iva, 1989. (Folder 77: 10)
        1 color print depicting Iva Procházková
      - Procházková, Lenka, n.d. (Folder 77: 11)
        2 black and white prints depicting Lenka Procházková
      - Provazníková, Marie, 1932-1933. (Folder 77: 12)
      - Rambousek, Ota, 1968. (Folder 77: 13)
        3 unidentified black and white prints, 3 color prints depicting Apolona and Ota Rambousek, 1 black and white print depicting Ota Rambousek
      - Rechner, Vincent, 1993. (Folder 77: 14)
        5 color prints depicting Josef Skvorecký, 9 unidentified color prints
      - Reichovi, n.d. (Folder 77: 15)
        4 unidentified color prints
      - Reiniš, Stanislav, n.d. (Folder 77: 16)
      - Řesáč, Jan, 1963. (Folder 77: 17)
        1 black and white print depicting Jan Řesáč
      - Řezníček, Ivo, 1984. (Folder 77: 18)
      - Roth, Susanna, 1987. (Folder 77: 19)
        6 black and white prints depicting Bohumil Hrabal
      - Salaquarda, Karel, n.d. (Folder 77: 20)
        2 color prints depicting Karel Salaquarda
      - Seifert, Jaroslav, 1984-1986. (Folder 77: 21)
        1 black and white print depicting Jaroslav Seifert, 2 unidentified color prints, 7 black and white prints depicting the Seifert funeral on March 21, 1986
      - Silhánek, V., n.d. (Folder 77: 22)
        5 color prints depicting Zdena Skvorecká
      - Simková, Daša, 1946-1978. (Folder 77: 23)
        2 unidentified color prints, 5 unidentified black and white prints, 1 black and white print depicting Daša Simková
      - Sjoeblom, Alice Babs, 1990-1992. (Folder 77: 24)
        3 color prints depicting Alice Babs Sjoeblom, 4 unidentified color prints, 2 unidentified black and white prints
      - Skácel, Jan, 1977-1980. (Folder 77: 25)
        19 unidentified black and white prints
      - Skov, Zuzana, 1980. (Folder 77: 26)
        8 unidentified color prints, 1 unidentified black and white print, 1 black and white print depicting Prague
      - Skutina, Vladimír, n.d. (Folder 77: 27)
        3 unidentified color prints, 1 black and white print depicting Martina Navrátilová as a child
      - Skvor, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 77: 28)
      - Skvorecká, Ema (Skvorecký's mother), 1920-1984. (Folder 77: 29)
        50 unidentified black and white prints
      - Slovník Spisovatelů, 1984. (Folder 77: 30)
        3 unidentified black and white prints, 1 color print depicting A. J. Liehm, 1 black and white print depicting Jiří Traxler
      - Souček, Jan, 1984. (Folder 77: 31)
        6 unidentified black and white prints, 1 black and white print depicting Václav Havel
      - Spaniel, Bohumír, 1973-1983. (Folder 77: 32)
        20 unidentified black and white prints, 3 unidentified color prints
      - Stafl, Jaja, n.d. (Folder 77: 33)
      - Staňková, Maruška, n.d. (Folder 77: 34)
        1 black and white print depicting Pandora Richardson
      - Stichová, Marie, n.d. (Folder 77: 35)
      - Stoppard, Tom, 1978. (Folder 77: 36)
        3 black and white prints depicting David Langton, William Marlowe, John Thaw, Olu Jacobs, and George Harris, 1 unidentified black and white print, 4 black and white prints depicting Peter Barkworth, 2 black and white prints depicting Stephen Rea, 2 black and white prints depicting John Shrapnel
      - Strož, Daniel, n.d. (Folder 77: 37)
        1 black and white print depicting Daniel Strož
      - Stuchliková, Jarka, n.d. (Folder 77: 38)
      - Sváb, Ludvík, 1965-1986. (Box-folder 78: 1)
        3 black and white prints and 1 color print depicting Jiřičce Jarka
      - Svestka, Jaroslav, 1989. (Folder 78: 2)
      - Sviták, Ivan, 1982. (Folder 78: 3)
        1 unidentified black and white print, 1 black and white print and 2 color prints depicting Ivan Sviták
      - Swinkels-Nováková, Michaela, 1981-1993. (Folder 78: 4)
        11 color prints depicting Michaela Swinkels-Nováková and family members
      - Syrovátko, Josef, 1985-1986. (Folder 78: 5)
        9 unidentified color prints, 1 color print depicting the Auschwitz concentration camp, 1 color print depicting Vašek Hvězda, 1 color print depicting Zdenička Kučerová, 1 color print depicting Mirek Celba
      - Taussig, Pavel, 1993-1994. (Folder 78: 6)
        1 black and white print depicting the documentary movie Ocelová cesta, 2 unidentified black and white prints, 1 black and white and 1 color print depicting Pavel Taussig and family members
      - Taylor, Líba, n.d. (Folder 78: 7)
        1 black and white print depicting a book by Jaroslav Seifert
      - Tigrid, Pavel, 1988. (Folder 78: 8)
        2 color prints and 1 black and white print depicting Pavel Tigrid
      - Tomský, Alexander, n.d. (Folder 78: 9)
        1 black and white print depicting Alexander Tomský
      - Traxler, Jiří, 1941-1984. (Folder 78: 10)
        17 unidentified black and white prints, 1 unidentified color print, 1 black and white print depicting Jiří Traxler, 1 black and white print depicting Kamil Běhounek and Vlasta Kloc, 1 black and white print depicting Jirka Baur and Karlíček, 1 black and white print depicting Luďa Kopecký, Mirek Kloc, Karel Sidla, and Jiří Jelínek, 1 black and white print depicting Kamil Běhounek
      - Třešňák, V., 1983. (Folder 78: 11)
        1 black and white print depicting Kormanová
      - Ulč, Ota, 1954-1984. (Folder 78: 12)
        39 unidentified black and white prints, 4 unidentified color prints, 1 color and 1 black and white print depicting Ota Ulč
      - Vaculík, Ludvík, n.d. (Folder 78: 13)
      - Valenta, Vladimír, 1970. (Folder 78: 14)
      - Veit, Vladimír, n.d. (Folder 78: 15)
      - Vejdělek, Čestmír, 1 black and white print depicting Čestmír Vejdělek (Folder 78: 16)
      - Vejvoda, Jaroslav, 1987-1988. (Folder 78: 17)
        5 unidentified color prints, 2 unidentified black and white prints, 2 black and white prints depicting Julius Effenberger
      - Vodňanský, Jan, 1979. (Folder 78: 18)
      - Voskovec, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 78: 19)
      - Weiss, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 78: 20)
        1 unidentified black and white print, 2 unidentified color prints
      - World Literature Today, 1980. (Folder 78: 21)
        1 black and white print depicting V. Mihailovic, G. Savidis, S. Kumar, I. Ivask, Arnošt Lustig, T. Keneally, A. Scott, C. Esteban, Y. Konaka, A. Brink, L. De Sousa
      - Zábrana, Jiří, 1975-1983. (Folder 78: 22)
        7 unidentified black and white prints, 1 black and white print depicting the grave of Rodina Pichová
      - Žekulin, 1992-1993. (Folder 78: 23)
      - Zelená, Marie, n.d. (Folder 78: 24)
      - Zemánková, Inka, n.d. (Folder 78: 25)
        10 black and white and 2 color prints depicting Inka Zemánková
  - Negatives, slides, and transparencies
    - Writings
      - Scherzo capriccioso (Dvořák novel), n.d. (Box-folder 79: 1)
        7 unidentified color negatives, 2 unidentified black and white negatives, 1 black and white negative depicting Adele Margulies
    - Correspondence
      - General. Painters (Malíři), 1988. (Folder 79: 2)
        11 unidentified color slides
      - Bartošek, Karel, n.d. (Folder 79: 3)
        1 unidentified transparency
      - Beneš, Jan, n.d. (Folder 79: 4)
        1 color transparency depicting the cover of Jan Beneš's book Zelenou nahoru
      - Bondy, Egon, 1981. (Folder 79: 5)
        1 unidentified color slide
      - Brychta, Lída and Jan, n.d. (Folder 79: 6)
        2 color transparencies and 1 color slide depicting paintings by Lída and Jan Brychta
      - Chadim, Václav, n.d. (Folder 79: 7)
        24 unidentified color negatives
      - Disher, Hanyi, n.d. (Folder 79: 8)
        1 unidentified color slide, 1 unidentified color transparency
      - Drozd, Karel, 1969. (Folder 79: 9)
        6 unidentified color slides
      - Dyntarová, Marie, n.d. (Folder 79: 10)
        4 unidentified black and white negatives
      - Hanzálek, Jiří, 1980. (Folder 79: 11)
        2 unidentified color slides
      - Harníček, Martin, n.d. (Folder 79: 12)
        1 unidentified black and white negative
      - Havel, Václav, n.d. (Folder 79: 13)
        25 black and white negatives depicting Olga and Václav Havel, 11 black and white negatives depicting letters to Olga
      - Havlínová, Alena, 1988. (Folder 79: 14)
        1 color slide and 1 color transparency depicting a painting by Alena Havlínová
      - Hejl, Vilém, 1966. (Folder 79: 15)
        1 color slide depicting the painting Mečový král
      - Hora, Karel, n.d. (Folder 79: 16)
        1 color slide depicting the painting Katedrála
      - Hostovský, Egon, n.d. (Folder 79: 17)
        1 black and white transparency depicting Egon Hostovský
      - Jazzová sekce svazu hudebníků ČSR, n.d. (Folder 79: 18)
        9 unidentified black and white negatives
      - Kliment, Alexandr, 1979. (Folder 79: 19)
        2 black and white negatives depicting Ivan Klíma, 1 unidentified color slide
      - Kriseová, Eda, n.d. (Folder 79: 20)
        1 unidentified color transparency
      - Kryl, Karel, 1973. (Folder 79: 21)
        1 color transparency and 6 color slides depicting paintings by Karel Kryl
      - Kundera, Milan, n.d. (Folder 79: 22)
        2 unidentified black and white slides, 1 color transparency depicting the cover of Milan Kundera's book Život je jinde
      - Linhartová, Věra, n.d. (Folder 79: 23)
        2 unidentified black and white negatives
      - Mandlová, Adina, n.d. (Folder 79: 24)
        12 unidentified color negatives
      - Mareš, Stanislav, n.d. (Folder 79: 25)
      - Ochová, Sheila, n.d. (Folder 79: 26)
      - Radová, Lucie, n.d. (Folder 79: 27)
        1 unidentified color transparency, 1 unidentified color negative
      - Richterová, Sylvie, n.d. (Folder 79: 28)
        2 unidentified color transparencies
      - Simková, Daša, n.d. (Folder 79: 29-30)
        7 unidentified color transparencies
      - Slovník Spisovatelů, n.d. (Folder 79: 31)
      - Sviták, Ivan, n.d. (Folder 79: 32)
        216 unidentified black and white negatives
      - Taylor, Líba, n.d. (Folder 79: 33)
        1 color slide depicting the frontpage of The European
      - Traxler, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 79: 34)
        4 unidentified color negatives
      - Vaculík, Ludvík, 1972-1974. (Folder 79: 35)
        11 unidentified black and white transparencies
      - Zábrana, Jiří, n.d. (Folder 79: 36)
        1 unidentified black and white negative, 1 unidentified color slide